Guide to the Thomas Parran Papers, 1892-1968 UA.90.F14
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Addresses and Meetings, VI.
  - Monroe County Medical Society University of Rochester: Eastman Kodak Company, Rochester, March 31, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 699)
  - Current Problems in Public Health. Opening remarks at 43rd Conference of State and Territorial Health Officers, April 9, 1945 (Box 46, Folder 700)
  - No title listed in finding aid (Box 47, Folder 701)
  - Testimony by Dr. Parran at hearings on H.R. 2992: To Extend Provisions of May Act, May 1, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 702)
  - U.S. - Mexico Border Public Health Association El Paso, May 14-16, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 703)
  - Pending Legislation re: Public Health and Hospitals for the Future Colorado State Medical Society, Denver, May 24, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 704)
  - Hearings before Subcommittee of Senate Committee on Appropriations re: Social Protection Division, FSA, June 14, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 705)
  - Surgeon General addressed medical and nursing graduates, Duke University, June 23, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 706)
  - Statement of Surgeon General Parran before Senate Committee on Education and Labor on S.l90 and S.1099 - Dental Bills, June 26, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 707)
  - Remarks by Surgeon General Parran at dinner of Variety Clubs of America to honor Sir Alex Fleming, July 25, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 708)
  - Red Cross Canteen Broadcast Washington, D.C., August 27, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 709)
  - "Hospitals Need Help" Radio broadcast on famous jury trials, WMAL, September 7, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 710)
  - Award presented by Dr. Parran at luncheon given by Advertising Club of Washington, D.C. in honor of Miss Helen Hayes, September 11, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 711)
  - Address on rural health at Georgia Conference on Social Welfare, Atlanta, September 13, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 712)
  - Health in the Postwar Period. Address by Dr. Parran at opening of George Washington University Medical School, September 17, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 713)
  - Statement of Dr. Parrin at hearings on S.1349: Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 before Senate Subcommittee, October 4, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 714)
  - Hearings on stream pollution bills, November 13, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 715)
  - Youth in the Atomic Age. Broadcast, WRC General Federation of Woments Clubs, November 30, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 716)
  - A National Health Program - American Style. U.S. Conference of Mayors, New York City, December 12, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 717)
  - The Medical Profession in a National Health Program Seaboard Medical Association, Virginia Beach, December 12, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 718)
  - Medical Centers of the Future. Mayo Memorial Lecture, Dartmouth Colleges, December 16, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 719)
  - Medical Centers of the Future. Mayo Memorial Lecture, Dartmouth Colleges, December 16, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 720)
  - "Exploring the Unknown" radio broadcast, station WOL, Washington, D.C. 9:00 p.m., ,(Revere Brass Copper Inc.), January 27, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 721)
  - The New Strategy Against Venereal Disease address at Social Hygiene Day luncheon Cleveland, February 5, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 722)
  - The Voluntary Hospital Looks Ahead, Address at 1946 convention of Methodist Hospitals and Homes Chicago, February 6, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 723)
  - Goals for National Health - How to win Them. Meeting of National Board of YWCA, Atlantic City, March 1, 1946. (Box 47, Folder 724)
  - Testimony by Dr. Parran on S.1160: To Establish National Neuropsychiatric Institute, March 6, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 725)
  - Medical Centers of the Future Revised manuscript of Dartmouth Speech for publication in Yale Review (Box 47, Folder 726)
  - Testimony by Dr. Parran and other statements on S.191: Hospital Survey and Construction Bill, March 7-8, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 727)
  - Testimony of Dr. Parran on H.R. 4502: Neely Cancer Bill. House Committee on Foreign Affairs, May 7, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 728)
  - Opportunities for the Medically Trained in Public Health. Pub. in The Diplomate of National Board of Medical Examinors, reprinted by permission of JAMA, May, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 729)
  - Nutrition in the Public Health Programs. Reprinted in Nutrition Reviews, May, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 730)
  - Extemporaneous remarks by Dr. Parran at Regional Directors meeting of Social Security Board, May 8, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 731)
  - Basic Significance of the Food and Drug Act in Public Health. At 40th anniversary of Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, New York City, June 25, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 732)
  - Seasonal Behavior of Polio. Article pub. in Hospitals, Vol. 20, June, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 733)
  - Remarks by Dr. Parran at showing of film "Clean Waters," in New York City, June 26, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 734)
  - Charter for World Health Closing address by Dr. Parran at International Health Conference, New York City, July 22, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 735)
  - Radio broadcast by Dr. Parran on Mutual WMAL, Tuesday, on Polio, August 13, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 736)
  - "Health Goals" address at National Medical Association, Louisville, KY, August 21, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 737)
  - Federal Hospital Council Meeting. Statement by Dr. Parran at opening session, September 17-19, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 738)
  - National and International Horizons in Health. Biennial Nursing Convention, HOPHN, Atlantic City, September 24, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 739)
  - "Washington Views" Interview with Barnet Nover, Recorded, September 26, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 740)
  - Convocation of American College of Hospital Administrators, Bellevue Stratford Hotel, Philadelphia, September 29, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 741)
  - American Hospital Association, remarks by Dr. Parran at general session of Committee on Hospital Care, Philadelphia, September 30, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 742)
  - "The Toll of Arthritis and Rheumatic Diseases in the U.S.O." Dinner given by National Arthritis Research Foundation, Astor Hotel, New York City, October 14, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 743)
  - The Effect of the School Lunch on Food Habits of Health National School Lunch Conference Washington, D.C., October 22, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 744)
  - Research and the Memorial Laboratory, by Jas. A. Crobtree at dedication of Memorial Laboratory NIH, October 27, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 745)
  - The World Health Organization - Corner Stone of Peace, by Parran and Boudreau. presented by Dr. Boudreau at APHA in Cleveland, November 12, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 746)
  - Our Common Problems Address at State Territorial Health Officers, December 3, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 747)
  - A National Cancer Policy Conference on Gastric Cancer, Billings Hospital, Chicago, December 5, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 748)
  - National Arthritis Research Foundation luncheon New York City, July 16, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 749)
  - Pharmacy International Article on Public Health Service, February, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 750)
  - Health of the Nation Statement before Subcommittee of Appropriations Committee, February 7, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 751)
  - Hospitals and the Health of the People. Address before Congress on Medical Education and Licensure AMA, Chicago, February 10, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 752)
  - Cancer testimony at Appropriations Subcommittee, February 17, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 753)
  - Research Programs and Planning of the U.S.P.H.S. Address before medical advisors, American Legion, February 20, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 754)
  - Statement before Senate Appropriations Committee on effect of reductions, March, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 755)
  - General statement re supplemental estimate of $1,000,000 to NIH (Sen. Doc. 44), March, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 756)
  - National Science Foundation Testimony on bills re above, before House Interstate and Foreign Committee, March 6-7, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 757)
  - The World Health Organization. Reprinted in Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine, v. 19, no.4, March, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 758)
  - Cancer Activities and Interests of the U.S. Public Health Service. Testimony before Interstate and Foreign Commerce Committee, March 11, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 759)
  - Health Pioneers Address at 150th anniversary of Boston Dispensary, Boston, March 17, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 760)
  - Red Cross broadcast, station WQQW, March 26, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 761)
  - 76th-77th Congressional Club. Remarks by Dr. Parran "Off the Record" held at Army-Navy Club, March 26, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 762)
  - Research and Total Health. Address (Kober Lecture) at Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., March 28, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 763)
  - "Next Steps" Annual drive of Visiting Nurse Assn, York, PA, April 10, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 764)
  - Boston Symphony Hour Broadcast WMAL, Washington, D.C., April 15, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 765)
  - Public Health Service and Industrial Pollution (prepared but not delivered by Parran at American Chemical Society, Atlantic City), April 19, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 766)
  - Stream Pollution - testimony before Subcommittee of Senate Committee on Public Works, S.418, April 22, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 767)
  - New Hope for the Handicapped Goodwill Industries luncheon meeting, Metro Clubs New York City, April 24, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 768)
  - Nursing in the International Health Program Opening session of International Council of Nurses, Atlantic City, May 12, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 769)
  - New Health Problems in the United States Address before joint meeting of State and Provincial Health Authority and Canadian Public Health Association Quebec, May 21, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 770)
  - Chicago-Cook County Health Survey. Address before annual meeting of Health Division, Council of Social Agencies, Chicago, May 26, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 771)
  - Research Program of the U.S. Public Health Service; lecture to faculty and students of Univ. of Calif., San Francisco, May 27, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 772)
  - Expanding Responsibilities and Opportunities in Public Health. Western Branch, American Public Health Assn., San Francisco, May 28, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 773)
  - Health Goals for Tomorrow at 60th anniversary, Denver Community Chest, Denver, June 2, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 774)
  - Your Part in the Nation's Health Program; address at 50th Convention of National Congress of Parents and Teachers, Chicago, June 3, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 775)
  - Prologue address at commencement exercises, Landon School, Bethesda, Md., June 6, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 776)
  - Your Nation. address at commencement, Marietta College, Mariettta, Ohio, June 8, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 777)
  - Testimony on H.J. Res. 161. World Health Organization before Subcomm. of House Foreign Affairs Committee, June 13, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 778)
  - Federal Health Legislation and its Relation to the Voluntary Hospital. Catholic Hospital Association, Boston, June 16, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 779)
  - World Health organization. Testimony on S.J. Res. 98 before Senate Foreign Affairs Committees, June 17, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 780)
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis. Movie short, June 27, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 781)
  - National Health Program. Testimony on S.1320 and S.545 before Subcommittee on Health of Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, July 9, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 782)
  - North Carolina's Place in National Health Program. Greensboro, N.C., July 11, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 783)
  - Pediatrics. 5th International Congress on welcome address, New York, July 15, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 784)
  - Progress Towards a National Health Program Address at meeting of New Jersey Health and Sanitary Assn. Atlantic City, October 8, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 785)
  - Surmounting Obstacles to Health Progress. Address at 75th annual meeting of A.P.H.A. Atlantic City, October 9, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 786)
  - The Nation Against Cancer. Address at Forum of Covenant Club of Illinois. Chicago, October 23, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 787)
  - Prudential Hour broadcast WTOP, October 13, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 788)
  - Medical Manpower. Address at Assn. of American Medical Colleges, Sun Valley, Idaho, October 28, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 789)
  - State and Territorial Health Officers meeting, December 2, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 790)
  - Maryland Congress of Parents and Teachers. Baltimore, (Dr. Parran spoke from notes), December 8, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 791)
  - The Control of Tuberculosis in the Americas. 12th Pan American Sanitary Conference, Caracas, January 20, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 792)
  - Are We Stamping Out Syphilis? Social Hygiene Day lunch, ASHA. Hotel Pennsylvania, February 4, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 793)
  - National Garden Conference, Washington, D.C. Remarks by Dr. Parran, February 2, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 794)
  - YMCA Transcription broadcast. WTOP-CBS, February 8, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 795)
  - Appropriation hearings before House of Rep., Subcommittee on 1949 Appro. estimates, Jan-Feb 1948 (Box 49, Folder 796)
  - American Heart Week radio broadcast, February 9, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 797)
  - The New National Health Programs and Research and the Nations Health, U. of Miami, Feb. 24-25, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 798)
  - Statement on SQ176, H.R. 4200, H.R. 574: Establish National Institute of Dental Research, March 11, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 799)
  - A.A.A.S. meeting Dr. Parran presiding. Speeches by Sopers, Sawyer, Warren, Faust, Sept. 15, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 800)
  - I.C.E.F. article - United Nations Bulletin, September 1948 (Box 49, Folder 801)
  - World Health and Hospitals. Address in Atlantic City. American Hospital Associatio, September 22, 1948 (Box 49, Folder 802)
  - Hospital Programs and Rural America. For publication in The Nation's Agriculture, November, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 803)
  - The International Health Conference. Address at Food and Nutrition Board, National Research Council, December 12, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 804)
  - Plain Words by Parran and Vonderlehr, October, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 805)
  - Plain words (Box 49, Folder 806)
  - Proposed Program for the Secretary of Wars The Secretary of the Navy, and the Federal Security Administration in connection with venereal disease control (Box 50, Folder 807)
- Miscellaneous Bibliography, VII.
  - Baruch, Bernard. Report on Physical Medicine (Box 50, Folder 808)
  - Bell, W.J. Trends in Public Health and Medical Care in Canada, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 809)
  - Berge, Wendell. "Justice and the Future of Medicine" 14th annual meeting of American Urological Assoc. St. Louis, June 21, 1944 (Box 50, Folder 810)
  - Biggs, Hermann M. Sanitary Regulations and Duty of the State in Regard to Public Hygiene, 1932 (Box 50, Folder 811)
  - Bousfield, 5f.D. (Dr.) Home and Health Education Program, 1937 (Box 50, Folder 812)
  - Brackenburg, Sir X. B. Health Insurance in England (Box 50, Folder 813)
  - Bretton Woods Proposal, 1945 (Box 50, Folder 814)
  - Bristol, Leverett D. 1937. "Preventive and Industrial Medicine and Public Health" A.M.A., July 1937 (Box 50, Folder 815)
  - Brookings Institute (Box 50, Folder 816)
  - Brown Dorothy Kirchwey. National League of Women Voters Federal Aid to the States, 1926 (Box 50, Folder 817)
  - Brunet, Walter M., M.D. Venereal Disease Prevalence in the City of New York, 1929 (Box 50, Folder 818)
  - Bundesen, Herman N. "Everybody's Problems", 1938 (Box 50, Folder 819)
  - Bunker, Henry A. (General Paralysis) (Box 50, Folder 820)
  - Bush, Vannevar. Report, Science - The Endless Frontier (Box 50, Folder 821)
  - The Provision of Adequate Medical Care by Allan M. Butler Reprinted from State Gov't., March 1944 (Box 50, Folder 822)
  - Butler, C.S. Syphilis - Woman's Problem. Yaws and Syphilis and other papers., Feb. 19, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 823)
  - Canada's Health Programme. Reprinted trom International Labor Office, no. 4 (Box 50, Folder 824)
  - Castelli, Professor Dr. Giorgio. On the Biological Testing of Arsenbenvoles (Box 50, Folder 825)
  - Carter, Henry Rose (Box 50, Folder 826)
  - Chener, Clarence O. (Asst. Director, Psyrchiatric Institute, N.Y.C.) Responsibilities of State Hospitals in the Treatment of Neurosyphilis in latent and active (Box 50, Folder 827)
  - Churchill, Winston (Box 50, Folder 828)
  - Clark, Talifeno, M.D. Control of Syphilis in Southern areas. A study by the U.S.P.H.S., Rosenwald Fund, etc., 1932 (Box 50, Folder 829)
  - Cohen, Colonel Samuel Adams. "Children and Adequate National Defense" (Box 50, Folder 830)
  - Cole, Earold N., M.D. (Moore, O'Leary, et al.) Syphilis in Pregnancy, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 831)
  - Mission to Tokyo by Karl T. Compton, October 26, 1945 (Box 50, Folder 832)
  - Cornely, Paul B. Post Graduate Medical Education in the United States. Cumming, Dr. Hugh S. Address given to senior class in Public Health, George Washington Medical School, July 31, 1944 (Box 50, Folder 833)
  - Committee on Economic Security Report to the President, 1935 (Box 50, Folder 834)
  - Walter Davenport. "Bad-blood Wagon." (Collier's.), May 27, 1949 (Box 50, Folder 835)
  - Planning the Hospital For Community Service by Mr. Graham Davis of W.K. Kellogg Foundation. Reprinted from Minn. Med., November 1946 (Box 50, Folder 836)
  - Davis, H. Jackson, M.D. Medical Care in New York State., 1933 (Box 51, Folder 837)
  - Davis, Michael M., M.D. Sickness Insurance and Medical Care, 1934. Wanted: Research in Econamsc and Social Aspects of Medicine, 1935. Aspects of Medicine, 1935. Syphilis as an Economic Problem, 1932. (Box 51, Folder 838)
  - Dalrymple-Champneys, Sir Weldon. The future of the isolation hospital, 1936 (Box 51, Folder 839)
  - De Kruife, Paul (Box 51, Folder 840)
  - Downing, John Godwin. Care of Syphilis in Out-Patient Department., Boston City Hospital, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 841)
  - Draper, George. Man and His Cures, 1923 (Box 51, Folder 842)
  - Dublin, Louis I. Public Health Service a Sound Investment, 1931 (Box 51, Folder 843)
  - Dunlap, Charles B. Recent Studies on Spirochetes in G.P. Anatomical Borderline Between So-called Syphilitic and Metasyphilitic Disorders, 1922 (Box 51, Folder 844)
  - The United Nations Conference on Food and Agriculture at Hot Springs. Lecture in British Norwegian Institute, London, by Dr. Karl Evans (Box 51, Folder 845)
  - Address by Mr. Oscar Ewing, Fed. Sec. Administrator at 46th annual Conference of State and Territorial Health Officers, December 2, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 846)
  - American Medical Association. Address by Fed. Sec. Administrator Oscar E. Ewing, Cleveland, January 7, 1948 (Box 51, Folder 847)
  - Falk, I.S. (Box 51, Folder 848)
  - Farrier and Warthin. Method for Demonstrating Spirocheta Pallida in Single Sections, 1930 (Box 51, Folder 849)
  - Ferrell, John A. A Few Health Problems Awaiting Solutions, 1935 (Box 51, Folder 850)
  - Fiertz, Charles O. Syphilis and Paresis. Malarial Treatment of General Paralysis (Box 51, Folder 851)
  - Fisher, Irving. Lengthening of Human Life, 1936 (Box 51, Folder 852)
  - Child Welfare, The Spearhead of Social Security? by Homer Folks before subcommittee at Round Table Conference, Washington, D.C., Wednesday, November 14, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 853)
  - Folks, Homer, LL.D. Jungle Rule of the Golden Rule. Wither Bound Relief. (Box 51, Folder 854)
  - Fraadsen, Helga. Hemeralopia as an early criterion of A - Avitaminosis, etc., 1935 (Box 51, Folder 855)
  - Frankel, Kee K., M.D. Lengthening the Span of Life., 1931 (Box 51, Folder 856)
  - Frost, Wade H., M.D. Outlook for Eradication of Tuberculosis. How much control of Tuberculosis?, 1935, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 857)
  - San Francisco Experience by J.C. Geiger (Box 51, Folder 858)
  - Gill, D.G., M.D. Syphilis in the Rural Negro. New Orleans, Louisiana., Southern Medical Association, November 18 - 20, 1931, 1931 (Box 51, Folder 859)
  - Godfrey, Edward S. Comparative Value of State Districts and County Districts as basis of local Health Organization, 1936 (Box 51, Folder 860)
  - Lawrence L. Gowrley, legal counsel, American Osteopathic Assoc. before subcommittee of Interstate and for Comm. on HR. 3924. (Box 51, Folder 861)
  - Haines, Blanche M., M.D. Maternal and infant mortality, 1931 (Box 51, Folder 862)
  - Harrison, L.W. The Venereal Diseases Schemes in England and Wales, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 863)
  - Harrison, L.W. Treatment of Syphilis, 1929 (Box 51, Folder 864)
  - Hektoen, Ludvig. The specificness of certain hemolytic streptocci, 1935 (Box 51, Folder 865)
  - Henderson, D.K. Tabes and Mental Disease Diagnosis of Cerebral Syphilis - T he Cerebro - Spinal Fluid, 1911 and 1912 (Box 51, Folder 866)
  - Heyman, Jacob and Ziegler, Floyd H. False Concepts of Diseases or Conditions as Psychogenic Foci, 1935 (Box 51, Folder 867)
  - Howell, William H., M.D. Trimble Lecture - Relations of Public Health and Medicine, 1929 (Box 51, Folder 868)
  - Jackson, Robert H. Back to the American Way, July 14, 1939 (Box 51, Folder 869)
  - Jennings, H.S., M.D., Ph.D. Public Health Progress and Race Progress - Are they Incompatible, 1927 (Box 51, Folder 870)
  - Kettering Foundation, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 871)
  - Kemp, Jarold E. The Influence of Inadequate treatment of early Syphilis on Incidence and Incubation period of neurosyphilis, 1936 (Box 51, Folder 872)
  - Kingsbury, John A. Adequate Health Service For All People, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 873)
  - Kirby, George H. (See also, Bunker) Alcohol, Syphilis and insanity. Treatment of Genl. Paralysis (Box 51, Folder 874)
  - Klein, Jacob E. Curability of Syphilis., 1936 (Box 51, Folder 875)
  - Kline, B.S. Evaluation of Results of Flocculation Tests in Recent Amer. Conf, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 876)
  - Kosmak, George W., M.D. Study of Maternal mortality - New York State., 1933 - 1934 (Box 52, Folder 877)
  - League of Nations, 1935 (Box 52, Folder 878)
  - Preventive Medicine by Dr. Perrin H. Long, September 30, 1946 (Box 52, Folder 879)
  - Lehman, Hon. Herbert H. Miscellaneous papers, 1934 (Box 52, Folder 880)
  - Lloyd - George, Hon. David "Abraham Lincoln." (Box 52, Folder 881)
  - American Population Trends and Their Implications, by Rev. Thos. F. Maher. Saint Patrick's Cathedral, N.Y.C., 1946 (Box 52, Folder 882)
  - Medicine - Comings and Goings of Epidemics by Dr. Geo. W. McCoy. (Box 52, Folder 883)
  - Mental Hygiene., 1936 - 38 (Box 52, Folder 884)
  - Is There Enough Manpower? By Harold W. Metz. Brookings Institution, 1942 (Box 52, Folder 885)
  - The Veterans Say - or Else. By Agnes E. Meyer in Colliers, October 12, 1946 (Box 52, Folder 886)
  - America's Home Front, By Agnes Meyer. Reprints which appeared in Washington Post, February 21 through June 13, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 887)
  - Epidemiology of Syphilis and Gonorrhea by Wm. N. Munson, M.D. Read at APHA mtg. Wash., October 24, 1932 (Box 52, Folder 888)
  - National Negro Health Week Broadcast., March 28, 1938 (Box 52, Folder 889)
  - Newsholme, Sir Arthur. A Conspectus of Public Health Work. Medical Care For All. WABC network, 1930, 1934 (Box 52, Folder 890)
  - Nutrition, 1944 (Box 52, Folder 891)
  - Pope's Encyclical letter of Pope Pius XI on Reconstructing the Social Order (Box 52, Folder 892)
  - Shyrock, Richard H., 1936 - 37 (Box 52, Folder 893)
  - American Journal of Public Health, October 1937 (Box 52, Folder 894)
  - Sigerist, Henry E. Medical Education. Socialized Medicine., 1940 - 41 (Box 52, Folder 895)
  - Snow, William F., January 1938 (Box 52, Folder 896)
  - Swing, Raymond, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 897)
  - Venereal Disease Control Work. Proceedings of conference, held in Washington, December 28-30, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 898)
  - Wadsworth etc. Preparation of Antigens from Cultures of Treponema Pallidum, 1930 (Box 52, Folder 899)
  - Statement by Vice Pres. Wallace on Board of Economic Warfare, June 29, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 900)
  - Warren, Carl, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 901)
  - Weiss, Mr. Myron. Dollarless Doctors and Penniless Patients, January 17, 1935 (Box 52, Folder 902)
  - Weyerbacher, A.F. The Social Aspects of Syphilis, 1935 (Box 52, Folder 903)
  - Wile, Udo J. Dementia Paralytica and Tabel, 1935 (Box 52, Folder 904)